只是为了向你证明什么是没有秘密的
Just to kind of demonstrate to you
that there's no mystery into what
是 Docker 映像。
is a Docker image.
我们要开始用手来运行 Docker 映像，对吧 ?
We're gonna start to run
a Docker image by hand, right?
使用之前我们所做的技术。
Using the same techniques
that we did before.
是啊只是为了证明他们只是把文件都压缩了差不多吧
Yeah, just to show that they're literally
just zip files, pretty much, right?
所以，预先制的容器叫做图像，对吧 ?
So, a pre-made container
is called an image, right?
你可以把你的图像从其他人的图像中拍摄下来，对吗 ?
And you can base your images off
of other people's images, right?
而你把它们叫做层次结构是相互顶着的。
And you kind of build these what they're
called is layers on top of each other.
基本上所有的图像都是把状态转出来
And basically an all in images
is it just dumps out the state
将它连接在一起或将其连接在一起。
of a particular container and
ties it together or zips it together.
事实上它确实是这样做的，对吗 ?
It's actually literally what it does,
right?
所以，让我们继续玩这个游戏。
So, let's go ahead and
have some fun with this.
所以我们要在码头的集装箱里做这个
So yeah, we're gonna do this
within a docker container.
所以我们要在码头集装箱内跑码头
So we're gonna run docker from
within a docker container.
这事有一定程度的对吧
There's some levels to this, right?
原因是我需要 Ubuntu，我现在在 Mac 上。
And the reason is I need Ubuntu,
and I'm on Mac right now.
所以如果你在这里运行这个容器
So if you run this container right here,
它要做的就是要运行一个码头的码头
what this is gonna do is it's going to
run a docker container that has a docker
与您的主机 VM 连接的客户机，对吗 ?
client that's connected to your host VM,
right?
或者你的电脑是吧
Or your host computer, right?
所以如果我要这样做
So if I run this, This is going to
连接到在我的 Docker 桌面上运行的 Docker 吗 ?
connect to my docker that's running
on my docker desktop right?
所以你现在可以看到，其实我是，如果猫的问题。
So you can see now,
I'm actually, if cat /etc/issue.
实际上我在阿尔派恩的 Linux 里
I'm actually within Alpine Linux,
and we'll talk about what
Alpine Linux 是后来的，但可以说我在 Linux 中，但如果我说过 docker ps的话，
Alpine Linux is later, but suffice to say
I'm within Linux, but if I say docker ps,
我可以看到我在运行的容器，对吗 ?
I can actually see the container
within which I'm running, right?
这是非典型的，通常您无法连接到主机外部，
This is atypical, typically you
cannot connect outside of the host,
但这就是这破折号的原料
but that's what this dash feed did.
它让我在它外面连接起来，对吧 ?
It allowed me to connect outside of it,
right?
所以我打开了一个隧道给主机， Docker 桌面。
So I opened a tunnel to the host,
Docker desktop.
同样，不要太担心这一问题的语义。
Again, don't worry too much
about the semantics of that.
知道我们正在连接到主机 Docker 容器。
Just know that we're connecting
to the host Docker container.
所以我就在那儿运行了这个命令
So I ran this command right there.
我现在想做的就是下载 Docker 容器。
So what I wanna do right now is I
want to download a Docker container.
然后我想去环境中分享它
And then I wanted to route into
the environment and unshare it and
然后将其添加到 C 组。
then add it to C groups.
我要离开 C 组因为我们看到了如何做到这一点
I'll leave out running the C groups
because we saw how to do that,
这有点烦人吗
tt's a bit burdensome?
我想你会相信我的对吧
So I think you'll trust me, right?
但我现在要做的就是我要说另一个 Docker 命令
But what I'm gonna do right now is I'm
gonna say another Docker command right
现在码头工人叫我叫我的高山
now, docker run -- rm
-dit --name my-alpine.
我们要跑高山 3.10
And we're gonna run Alpine : 3.10,
我们要从那个范围内跑来
and we're gonna run
shell from within that.
现在这一切都要做了
Now all this is gonna do,
这将会在后台启动一个容器就是我们在这里做的
this is gonna start a container in
the background, that's all we did here.
所以如果我再看 docker PS 你就能看到你
So if I look in docker PS again,
you can see you right there
我把这个容器命名为我的高山
I have this container here which
I have named my alpine and
都是在跑，什么都没做，就跑了。
all is doing it's just running,
not doing anything, just running.
我为什么要这样做
Now why did I do this?
我要把这个国家扔出去
I'm going to dump the state
out of this right and
然后我就把它作为自己的容器运行，这正是一个图像。
then I'm gonna run it as my own container,
which is exactly what an image is.
所以我要说码头出口 -o
So I'm going to say docker export -o
dockercontainer.tar ，类似于 Linux 的 zip 文件。
dockercontainer.tar, which is
like a zip file right, for Linux.
我要把我的高山倒掉
And I'm going to dump out
the state of my alpine.
你现在可以看到我有了这个码头
So you can see now I have
this dockercontainer.tar,
这就是那个集装箱的状态
this is the state of
what that container is.
现在，我将创建一个目录， mkdir container-root。
Now I'm going to make a directory,
mkdir container-root.
我要说焦油 xf
And I'm gonna say tar xf.
我永远都不记得焦油的旗帜了
I can never remember the flags for tar.
Dockercontainer.tar -C 容器-root/ 这将转至，
Dockercontainer.tar -C
container-root/ this is going to,
如果我看看现在的容器内部，看起来很熟悉，对吧 ?
if I look inside of container-root now,
looks pretty familiar, right?
看起来是另一个 Linux 文件系统。
Looks like another file system for Linux.
这就是它的存在
Again, that's what it is.
所以现在这个我也应该很熟悉的
So now,
this should feel very familiar too if I
说 unshare --mount --uts --ipc --net
say unshare --mount --uts --ipc --net
--pid --fork --user -- ，您可以复制和
--pid --fork --user --, you can copy and
如果你不是像我一样的惩罚
paste this if you are not a glutton for
punishment like I am.
映射 root 用户，并且我要将 root 用户更改为 root 用户，并且
Map-root-user and I'm gonna say
change root to container root and
我不去跑了，我要跑个不同的
I am not going to run bash,
I am going to run a different
叫做灰因为它是阿尔卑斯的权利不是 Ubuntu
called ash because it is Alpine right,
it is not Ubuntu.
我想你也可以说贝壳
I think you could just say shell as well.
好了，现在你可以看到，如果我运行 pwd ，你可以看到我在根目录中。
Okay, now you can see If I run pwd,
you can see I'm in the root directory.
现在，我无法共享此 Docker 容器映像。
I am unshared now into this
docker container image.
如果你能做典型的安装程序
And if you could do the typical
mount procs none/ proc,
安装- t sysfs 无/系统
mount- t sysfs none/sys
N mount-t tmpfs none/temp。
N mount-t tmpfs none/temp.
然后我就能拯救和一样的东西了对吧
Then I can save ps aux and
the same thing, right.
我可以看到它在运行外壳，等等，对吧 ?
I can see it's running the shell,
so on and so forth, right?
所以我基本上执行了这个 Docker 映像，但是
So I have essentially executed
this Docker image, but
我用以前的技术做过
I've done it with the previous techniques.
再一次，我还没有把它分组在一起。
And again, I haven't c grouped this.
但如果你想的话你可以去做那首歌
But if you wanted to,
you could go and do that song and
如果你想再跳舞
dance again if you wanted to.
所以，再一次， Docker 映像是什么，对不对 ?
So again, there's no mystery to
what Docker images are, right?
它们差不多就是 zip 文件，对，进去，为您运行这些命令。
They're pretty much just zip files, right,
that go in and run these commands for you.
同样， Docker 正在为您做更多的工作。
Again, Docker is doing more than that for
you.
它正在连接卷并通过安装一些其他类似的有用的东西
It's connecting volumes and by mounting
a bunch of other like useful things for
你，我可以教你，对你不太有用
you, that I could teach you,
that would not be very useful to you
因为你不会用手的对吧
because you would never do it by hand,
right?
我只是向你展示这些东西是它的
That I'm just kind of showing you that
these are the sorts of things that it's
在车篷下面为你做的事
doing underneath the hood for you.
但这是你永远无法理解的复杂性，对吧 ?
But this is complexity that you
never have to understand, right?
你从不需要但我觉得这对你来说是有用的
You never needed to but it's I think
it's useful for you to know, yeah.
>> 在更改根之后的上一个命令上，
&gt;&gt; On that previous command
after you change root,
你不需要这个 pwd/container吗 ?
you don't need the pwd/container?
>> 否 >> 在那里，是的。
&gt;&gt; No
&gt;&gt; Right there, yeah.
>> 这一权利 ?
&gt;&gt; This one right?
>> 您是否需要以 pwd 为前缀 ?
&gt;&gt; You dont need to prefix with pwd?
>> 否，所以在我的注释中，只是为了确保它始终工作
&gt;&gt; No, so I have that in my notes, just
to make sure that it would always work
取决于放置容器根的位置，对。
depending on where you put
that container root, right.
所以那里的人
So the pwd there,
就像你现在的工作目录，对吧 ?
all it's going to do is like your
present working directory, right?
但是因为我知道我把 Docker 容器放在根里，对，
But because I know I put that Docker
container in the roots, right,
就在那儿
it's right there.
是啊所以没必要
That yeah, so it wasn't necessary.
只是确定路径是正确的
It's just making sure the path is correct.
所以我们可以退出我们还在阿尔派恩
So we can exit out of that and
we are still within Alpine or
Docker 容器，对吗 ?
the Docker container, right?
所以我们在一个容器里做了一个容器，总是很有趣的，对吧 ?
So we did a container within a container,
which is always kinda fun, right?
但现在我可以退出了再一次
But now I can exit out of that,
which again,
会毁了你的整个环境但现在我又回到了 macOS
will destroy your entire environment,
but now I'm back in macOS.